Karthik Padav

karthikpadav@gmail.com https://karthikpadav.vercel.app linkedin.com/in/karthik-padav +91 9901373620

I'm a Software Developer with over 8 years of experience, Specialising in React.js. I enjoy creating user-friendly solutions and have a background in both Front-End and Back-End development. Whether it's building dynamic web applications or mobile solutions with React Native, I bring a passion for clean code and effective design to every project.

SKILLS

JavaScript, React js, Redux toolkit, Redux thunk, Next js, Vue js, Ionic-v1, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, Bootstrap, Ant design, CSS3, HTML5, JQuery, Photoshop, Node js, Express, React Native, Socket.io, Angular js and WordPress

EXPERIENCE

Luxoft, Bangalore — Senior Software Engineer

JANUARY 2023 - PRESENT

- High-performance application built using ReactJs v18, reduxjs/toolkit with redux thunk, React Hooks, Custom Hooks, React-Router, JavaScript, Ant design, and Formik
- Develop and maintain stable codebases.
- Conduct bug fixes and participate in code reviews.
- Ensure comprehensive documentation and reporting throughout the development lifecycle.
- Code merging and building/deploying the code to the central server.
- Agile Methodologies for incremental development to deliver better applications

Tecnotree, Bangalore — Senior Software Engineer

NOVEMBER 2019 - JANUARY 2023

- Developed high-performance application using ReactJs, Redux, React Hooks, React-Router, JavaScript, Html5, Material UI, and Formik
- Use of react-jsonschema-form to create A simple React component capable of using JSON Schema to declaratively build and customise web forms.
- Built reusable custom components for UX-library consisting of Accordion, Filters, DropDown, Modal PopUp, and Icons.
- Maintained high-level expertise in React state management strategies including Redux, and Redux Persist.
- Exclusively used React-Hooks to handle application life-cycle processes.
- Worked in Agile Methodologies for incremental development to deliver better applications

The Fuller Life, Bangalore — Front-End developer

OCTOBER 2017 - AUGUST 2019

- Implemented a mobile-first approach to existing websites.
- Worked on several Health and wellness, and employee engagement websites using Vue js, React js, Redux, HTML5, Bootstrap, and Bulma
- Designing and implementing HTML email templates and newsletters for marketing campaigns.

Codecraft Technologies, Bangalore — Front-End developer

MARCH 2016 - OCTOBER 2017

- Designed dynamic and multi-browser compatible web pages using HTML, CSS, Angular
- Communication-Timeline application about all Creative experiences between Creator and User/Fan using IONIC v1
- Dashboard for survey app using Angular, Bootstrap
- An application that helps you to book an ambulance during the time of a medical emergency using Template7 and JQuery
- Worked on the E-commerce website and on several Real Estate websites using HTML5 and Bootstrap

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Engineering In Computer Science

2012 - 2015

Shree Devi Institute of Technology, Mangalore (VTU, Belgaum)

Diploma In Computer Science

2009 - 2012

P.A Polytechnic (DTE, Karnataka)

DEMO PROJECTS

Movies And TV Shows

React js, Next js, Material UI
List of all new Movies and TV
shows with ratings and reviews.
All contents are fetched from
TMDB

<u>Did You Know? - Facts</u> Unlimited

React Native

Option to share interesting facts among your friends and families or on other social media.

The Color Picker

React js, Next js, Tailwind CSS Color patterns inspired by thousands of beautiful color schemes.

Instagram downloader

React Native

Android app that helps you download Instagram Videos, Photos, IGTV & albums.

All India pin code directory

React Native

This Application allows users to get Post Office details by searching Postal PIN Code or Post Office Branch Name.

HD Gaming wallpaper

React Native

HD Gaming wallpaper is an Android app with a collection of wallpapers.